Guide to the Henry Raup Wagner Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Henry Raup Wagner papers
1917-1962
1930-1952
WA MSS S-1299
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
17.5
(37 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence with scholars and members of the rare book world, notes and drafts related to Henry Wagner's published works, and other papers related to Wagner's research.
Wagner, Henry R. (Henry Raup), 1862-1957
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The papers were donated by Henry R. Wagner.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
HENRY RAUP WAGNER, 1862-1957
Henry Raup Wagner, known for his contributions to the bibliography and scholarship of the American and Spanish-American West, attended Yale College and Law School. Wagner eventually entered the mining business, spending most of his career working for the Guggenheim's American Smelting and Refining Company. Retiring in 1917, he married Blanche Henrietta Collet and settled in California. Most of Wagner's scholarly work dates from after his retirement.
Wagner's interest in rare books began in the 1880s. Although his collecting fields changed over the years, he eventually focused on Western Americana, using his collections to write bibliographies such as The Plains and the Rockies and The Spanish Southwest. In addition, he wrote on a variety of topics from the cartography of the West coast to Fernando Cortés.
Wagner was active in the California Historical Society, the Cortés Society, and the Quivira Society, and served as president of the Historical Society of Southern California in 1933-34. He was a good friend to many libraries. He not only donated works to the Bancroft Library, the Henry E. Huntington Library, the John Carter Brown Library, and the Yale University Library, but also served on committees to promote and support these institutions.
Further information on Wagner and his work can be found in his autobiography Bullion to Books (1942). The Published Writings of Henry R. Wagner (New Haven: William Reese Company, announced for 1987) contains a biographical essay by Stephen A. Colston, and a list of books about Wagner.
Scope and Contents
The Henry Raup Wagner Papers document his work as a bibliographer and historian of the American and Spanish-American West. The collection spans the dates 1917-1962, but the bulk of the material falls in the years 1930-1952.
The Wagner collection is organized into three series. Series I, Correspondence, provides information on Wagner's association with the rare book and scholarly worlds. Works from The Published Writings, Series II, chronicles Wagner's research and publication activity. Series III, Research Files, documents subjects Wagner studied and includes personal papers.
Series I, Correspondence, is arranged alphabetically by individual or corporate name. Appropriate cross-references have been made for significant individuals whose letters are filed under corporate bodies. The majority of the files contain letters to Wagner and copies of his replies.
Wagner sought research assistance from libraries and was in turn used as a source of information. Randolph Adams of the William L. Clements Library questioned Wagner on Mexican incunabula, and many libraries discussed their acquisitions and business affairs with him. Most of the letters from libraries, however, are form letters thanking Wagner for the books he donated.
Wagner's correspondence with scholarly societies focuses on publication issues. He served as editor for the Cortés Society, and was often consulted by the Quivira Society. Publishing questions even dominate correspondence with the Historical Society of Southern California, but since Wagner was the society's president from 1933-34, the letters document other business as well.
Wagner's letters show how he conducted researched, how he found publishers, and to whom he turned for comments. An excellent example is Nueva Bibliografía del Siglo XVI, Suplemento to a las Bibliografías de Don Joaquín García Icazbalceta, number 135 in The Published Writings of Henry R. Wagner. Icazbalceta was a Mexican bibliographer, whose grandson Joaquin Garcia Pimentel supplied Wagner with bibliographic information for his Suplemento, while G. R. G. Conway helped Wagner gather the history of Icazbalceta's library. Publishing Nueva Bibliografía proved a problem, as correspondence with the Bibliographical Society of America and the Grolier Club demonstrates. With the help of Pimentel, Federico Gómez de Orozco, and Jesús Guisa y Azevedo, Wagner eventually published the work in Spanish, an undertaking he discussed in depth with Lawrence Wroth.
Wagner enjoyed long friendships with George P. Hammond and Thomas W. Streeter. Their correspondence files are the largest in the series and cover all aspects of Wagner's scholarly career. Hammond, director of the Bancroft Library and active member of the Cortés Society and the Quivira Society, discussed the business affairs of these groups, particularly the formation of the Friends of the Bancroft Library. Wagner and Hammond also exchanged information on Mexican history and rare books. The correspondence of Thomas W. Streeter, bibliographer and collector, provides a fascinating account of the rare book world of the 1930s and 1940s.
Series II, Works from The Published Writings, is arranged according to the bibliography The Published Writings of Henry R. Wagner (chronologically by date of publication). In the "Box and Folder List," material is identified by numbers from the bibliography and short title. Series II contains Wagner's research files and papers concerning the publication of each work. He often bound these files, establishing a specific order; this arrangement has been maintained and applied to unbound papers.
The pattern of Wagner's arrangement is: a copy of the text, correspondence, notes, reproductions, and reviews. The offprint or typescript draft of each work is usually annotated by Wagner. Correspondence with the publisher or printer usually follows, along with receipts for binding and printing. Often research letters and comments from other scholars are included. Since Wagner gave copies of his works to friends and libraries, presentation lists and letters of acknowledgment may also be found in the correspondence. Notes and reproductions come next, though their order varies. Most of Wagner's notes are typewritten lists or prose sketches. Reproductions of primary documents (typescripts, photocopies, photographs) were used for research and often became part of the printed work as illustrative material. Finally, there are reviews, usually concerning his earlier books.
Not every work listed in Series II is fully documented. Of the described material, copies of the text and correspondence are the most common. The background material for The Plains and the Rockies (7, 8), Spanish Southwest (26), Discovery of New Spain (118), Rise of Cortés (124), and Nueva Bibliografía (135) is exceptional. The files for these works are good examples of the contents of Series II, Works from The Published Writings.
The Plains and the Rockies files include evidence of the physical production of the 1920 edition and both 1921 editions. Wagner often issued two editions of his books, one normal copy and one enhanced with photo-reproductions. Orders for facsimiles, correspondence with the printers, printing and binding receipts, presentation and purchase lists, trace the creation of these fine editions.
Spanish Southwest files, which include numerous typescripts, especially of individual bibliographic entries, notes, and correspondence with libraries, gives evidence about Wagner's research methods. Though correspondence usually relates only to publication and public reaction, Wilberforce Eames's letters, here and elsewhere, cover both research and printing.
Discovery of New Spain contains correspondence with the Cortés Society, publisher of the work. Some of these files are of general interest, documenting the group's publishing activities. Similarly, correspondence files in Series II for the Antiquarian Society, the Bibliographical Society of America, the California Historical Society, the Hispanic America Historical Review, the Historical Society of Southern California, and the Zamorano Club, all of which published works by Wagner, contain much general information about the group.
Rise of Cortés is the most fully documented work in Series II. Every type of material is included, together with notes for Wagner's lecture on Cortés to the Zamorano Club. There is a complete typescript draft and a set of photo-reproductions used as plates. Notes for the work consist of a series of typewritten prose sketches, lists, and transcripts of historic documents.
Series III, Research Files, is arranged alphabetically by headings, many of which were supplied by Wagner. The material is similar to that in Series II and is arranged the same way. Though most files contain a typescript and some pre-draft material, there is no correspondence or publication information. Of particular interest is "Spanish Southwest 1795-1845," a short typescript, which may be an introduction to a continuation of Spanish Southwest, 1542-1794 (26). The series contains a great deal of material related to a bibliography of Texas, including an extensively annotated version of C. W. Raines's Bibliography of Texas (1896). Some of Wagner's more personal papers are also housed in Series III.
Hispanic American historical review; Imago Mundi: Review of Early Cartography; Bibliography; Book collecting; Book collectors; Mexico -- Imprints; Southwest, New -- Imprints; West (U.S.) -- Bibliography; Bibliography -- United States; Photoprints -- United States; Bibliographers -- United States; Bagrow, Leo, 1881-1951; Brigham, Clarence S. (Clarence Saunders), 1877-1963; Caughey, John Walton, 1902-1995; Childs, James B. (James Bennett), 1896-1977; Coney, Donald; Conway, G. R. G. (George Robert Graham), 1873-1951; Duke, Elizabeth F. (Elizabeth Foster); García Pimentel, Joaquín; Hammond, George P. (George Peter), 1896-1993; Harding, Dorothy Huggins, 1894-; King, James F.; Lanning, John Tate, 1902-1976; Lydenberg, Harry Miller, 1874-1960; McCombs, Nelson N.; Powell, Lawrence Clark, 1906-2001; Shearer, Augustus Hunt, 1878-1941; Sproul, Robert Gordon, 1891-1975; Streeter, Thomas W. (Thomas Winthrop), 1883-1965; Wagner, Henry R. (Henry Raup), 1862-1957; Wroth, Lawrence C. (Lawrence Counselman), 1884-1970; American Antiquarian Society; Bibliographical Society of America; California Historical Society; Historical Society of Southern California; John Carter Brown Library; University of California, Berkeley; University of Texas at Austin; Yale University
- Correspondence, 1921-55; Series I; 2.25; (6 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, is housed in Boxes 1-6. The material is arranged alphabetically by surname of an individual or the organization and then chronologically. In a few cases other material, such as papers of a society, have been placed with the correspondence.
  - "A" general, 1948-50 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Academy of American Franciscan History, 1949-50 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adams, Randolph G.
    Related Archival Materials note
    See: Box 5, folder 124
  - American Antiquarian Society, 1935-50 (Box 1, Folder 3-6)
  - "B" general, 1939-49 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Babb, James T.
    See: Box 5-6, folders 125-3
  - Bagrow, Leo
    See: Box 3, folder 73
  - Bancroft, Eleanor, 1943-47 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bancroft Library
    See: Box 1, folders 8, 31-32; Box 2, folders 49-57; Box 4-5, folders 95-114
  - Bibliographical Society of America, 1934-45 (Box 1, Folder 9-11)
  - Brigham, Clarence S.
    See: Box 1, folders 3-6
  - "C" general, 1939-50 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - California Historical Society, 1928-51 (Box 1, Folder 13-16)
  - Camp, Charles L., 1944 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Caughey, John W.
    See: Box 5, folder 119
  - Childs, James B.
    See: Box 1, folders 9-11
  - Claremont Colleges Library, 1937-39 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Coney, David
    See: Box 5, folder 121
  - Conway, G. R. G., 1931-39 (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
  - Cortés Society, 1943-48 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    See also: Box 1, folder 8
  - "D" general, 1945, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Eastwood, Alice, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Eberstadt, Edward, 1948-49 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "F" general, 1938-46 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Farquhar, Francis P., 1944-50 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Foster, Elizabeth
    See also: Box 1, folders 8, 21
    - Correspondence, 1941-48 (Box 1, Folder 27-29)
    - Wagner's notes on Motolina, [ca. 1940s] (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Friends of the Bancroft Library
    - Correspondence, 1947-48 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Papers of the Friends (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Garcia Pimentel, Joaquin, 1934-43 (Box 2, Folder 33-41)
    See also: Box 1, folders 19-20; Box 2, folders 42, 47
  - Gómez de Orozco, Federico, 1937-39 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    See also: Box 2, folders 33-41
  - Grabhorn, Jane
    See: Colt Press, "C" general, Box 1, folder 12
  - Grabhorn Press, 1935-44 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Graff, Everett D., 1947-49 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Grannis, Ruth S.
    See: Box 2, folder 46
  - Grauer, Ben, 1946 Jun 8 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Grolier Club, 1932-49 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Guisa y Azevedo, Jesús, 1945-46 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    See also: Box 2, folders 33-42
  - "H" general, 1940-49 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Hammond, George P., 1940-50 (Box 2, Folder 49-57)
    See also: Box 1, folders 16
    See also: Box 1, folders 31-32
  - Hanna, Phil Townsend, 1939-48 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Harding, George L., 1947-48 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Hispanic American Historical Review, 1940-48 (Box 3, Folder 60-63)
  - Historical Society of Southern California
    - Correspondence, 1933-35 (Box 3, Folder 64-69)
    - Material regarding 50th anniversary celebration, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Papers of the Society, 1930-50 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Huggins, Dorothy H.
    See: Box 1, folders 13-16
  - Imago Mundi: Review of Early Cartography, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Instituto Nacional de Investigaciones, 1931 Apr 20 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - John Carter Brown Library, 1934-49 (Box 3, Folder 74-79)
  - Kerr, Willis H.
    See: Box 1, folder 18
  - Kessler, Charles N., 1948 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - King, James F.
    See: Box 3, folders 60-63
  - "L" general, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Lanning, John Tate
  - Lydenburg, H. M.
    See: Box 3, folder 85
  - "M" general, 1933-50 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - McCombs, Nelson N.
  - Museum of New Mexico, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - "N" general, 1934-45 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - New York Public Library, 1936-39 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Newberry Library, 1934-35 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Oehler, Mrs. James C., 1949 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - "P" general, 1948, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Pomona College Library
    - Correspondence, 1929-37 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - Material regarding Wagner's honorary degree, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 90)
      See also: Oversize, Box 35, folder 431
  - Powell, Lawrence Clark
  - Quivira Society, 1929-39 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    See also: Box 2, folders 49-57
  - "R" general, 1944-56 (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - "S" general, 1935-50 (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Sheares, Augustus H.
  - Southwest Museum, 1934-51 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Sproul, Robert G.
  - Streeter, Thomas W., 1929-50 (Box 4, Folder 95-107)
  - Streeter, Thomas W., 1951-52 (Box 5, Folder 108-14)
  - Sullivan, Maurice, 1933-34 (Box 5, Folder 115)
    See also: Missouri Historical Society, "M" general, Box 3, folder 82
  - "T" general, 1935-48 (Box 5, Folder 116)
  - "U" general, 1948-49 (Box 5, Folder 117)
  - Ugarte, Salvador, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 118)
  - University of California
    - Correspondence, 1939-50 (Box 5, Folder 119)
    - Material regarding Wagner's honorary degree, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 120)
      See also: Oversize, Box 35, folder 432
  - University of Texas, Austin, 1937-40 (Box 5, Folder 121)
  - Utley, George B.
    See: Box 3, folder 86
  - Valtón, Emilio, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 122)
  - Wheat, Carl, 1950, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 123)
    See also: Box 3, folders 64-71
  - William L. Clements Library, 1935-41 (Box 5, Folder 124)
  - Wroth, Lawrence
    See: Box 3, folders 74-79
  - Yale University
    - Correspondence with Library, 1921-49 (Box 5, Folder 125-27)
    - Material regarding Wagner's honorary degree, 1946-47 (Box 6, Folder 128-30)
      See also: Oversize, Box 35, folder 433
  - Zamorano Club
    - Correspondence, 1947-48 (Box 6, Folder 131)
    - Materials regarding celebration of Wagner's 85th birthday, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 132-33)
    - Programs, 1932-49 (Box 6, Folder 134)
- Works from The Published Writings, 1917-55; Series II; 7.25; (19 boxes)
  Series II, Works from The Published Writings, is housed in Boxes 7-24. The material is arranged according to the bibliography The Published Writings of Henry R. Wagner, New Haven: William Reese Company, announced for 1987. The numbers in parentheses are from this bibliography. For most works material can be found in this order: offprint, typescript or draft of the work, correspondence concerning publication, notes, and reproductions of primary documents.
  - Published Writings of Henry R. Wagner, New Haven: William Reese Company, ca. 1987 (Galley proofs), n.d. (Box 7, Folder 135)
  - (5, 6) List of Works relating to those Portions of the United States which formerly belonged to Mexico and Supplement, 1917-18 (Box 7, Folder 136)
  - (7) The Plains and the Rockies, 1918-21 (Box 7, Folder 137-40)
  - (8) The Plains and the Rockies, 1920-22 (Box 7, Folder 141)
  - (9) California Imprints, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 142-43)
    See also: Oversize, Box 35, folder 434
  - (11) "Discovery of California", 1922 (Box 8, Folder 144)
  - (26) Spanish Southwest and related bibliographies
    - The Spanish Southwest, [ca. 1924] (Box 8, Folder 145-46)
    - Cabeza de Vaca, [ca. 1924] (Box 8, Folder 147)
      Separately bound bibliography.
    - de Herrera, [ca. 1924] (Box 8, Folder 148)
    - Gonzales de Mendoza, [ca. 1924] (Box 8, Folder 149)
    - Lopez de Gomara, [ca. 1924] (Box 9, Folder 150)
  - (27) "Sixteenth Century Mexican Imprints", 1922-25 (Box 9, Folder 151)
  - (30) "California Voyages", 1924-25 (Box 9, Folder 152)
  - (32) "Some Imaginary California Geography", 1925-27 (Box 9, Folder 153)
  - (35) Sir Francis Drake's Voyage, 1927-34 (Box 9, Folder 154)
  - (48) "The Portolan Atlases", 1948-49 (Box 9, Folder 155)
  - (49) "Three accounts of the Expedition of Fernando Cortés"
    See: Oversize, Box 35, folder 435
  - (52) "Pearl Fishing Enterprises", 1929-30 (Box 10, Folder 156)
  - (56) "Apocryphal Voyages", 1931-32 (Box 10, Folder 157)
  - (57) The Earliest Documents of El Pueblo de Nuestra, 1930-32 (Box 10, Folder 158)
  - (59) "The Manuscript Atlases of Battista Agnese", 1928-32 (Box 10, Folder 159)
  - (62) "Biblio-cartography", 1931-32 (Box 10, Folder 160)
  - (64) The First Issue of the Los Angeles Star, 1932-33 (Box 10, Folder 161-62)
    See also: Oversize, Box 35, folder 436
  - (66) "The Names of the Channel Islands", 1934 (Box 11, Folder 163)
  - (67) "Fr. Marcos de Niza", 1932, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 164)
  - (69) Published Writings of Henry R. Wagner, 1931-35, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 165)
  - (70) "Joaquín García Icazbalceta", 1932-39 (Box 11, Folder 166)
  - (74) "The Life of Ferdinard C. Ewer", 1934-35 (Box 11, Folder 167)
  - (75) "Letter of José Maria Flores", 1935 (Box 11, Folder 168)
  - (76) "The Secularization of the Missions", 1935 (Box 11, Folder 169)
  - (77) Cartilla para Enseñar a Leer, 1935, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 170)
  - (79) Short Ravelings from a Long Yarn, 1935-36 (Box 12, Folder 171)
  - (80) "Journal of Tomás de Suría", 1935-36 (Box 12, Folder 172)
  - (81) "Four Early Sketches of Monterey Scenes", 1936 (Box 12, Folder 173)
  - (83) Letters of Captain Don Pedro Fages, 1936-37 (Box 12, Folder 174)
  - (84) "New Mexico Spanish Press", 1934, 1936 (Box 12, Folder 175)
  - (84) "New Mexico Spanish Press", 1937 (Box 13, Folder 176)
  - (85) Henry Wagner's The Plains and the Rockies, 1934-37 (Box 13, Folder 177)
  - (86) The Cartography of the Northwest Coast of America, 1931-48 (Box 13, Folder 178-92)
  - (87) The Spanish Southwest, 1936-37 (Box 13, Folder 193)
  - (91) The Grabhorn Press, 1935-38 (Box 14, Folder 194)
  - (96) "Creation of Rights of Sovereignty", 1938 (Box 14, Folder 194.1-95)
  - (98) Willard Samuel Morse, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 196)
  - (99) Mexican Imprints, 1938-39 (Box 14, Folder 197)
  - (100) "The Procesco", 1934-40 (Box 14, Folder 198)
  - (102) "Commercial Printers of San Francisco", 1939 (Box 14.1, Folder 199)
  - (104) "Ascents of Popocatepetl", 1939-40 (Box 14.1, Folder 200)
  - (106) "Francisco de Ulloa Returned", 1940 (Box 14.1, Folder 201)
  - (107) Juan Rodriguez Cabrillo, 1941 (Box 15, Folder 202)
  - (108) Collecting (Especially Books), 1941 (Box 15, Folder 203)
  - (109) "The Lost First Letter of Cortés", 1941-42 (Box 15, Folder 204)
  - (110) "Early Franciscan Activities", 1941 (Box 15, Folder 205)
  - (111) The Discovery of Yucatan, 1941-42 (Box 15, Folder 206)
  - (111) The Discovery of Yucatan, 1941-42 (Box 16, Folder 207)
  - (112) "Early Silver Mining in Spain", 1940-42 (Box 16, Folder 208)
  - (113) Bullion to Books, [ca. 1942] (Box 16, Folder 209)
  - (118) The Discovery of New Spain, 1939-43 (Box 17, Folder 210-20)
  - (120) "Edward Bosqui", 1938-42 (Box 18, Folder 221)
  - (124) The Rise of Fernando Cortés, [ca. 1943] (Box 18, Folder 222-34)
  - (124) The Rise of Fernando Cortés, [ca. 1943] (Box 19, Folder 235-50)
  - (124) The Rise of Fernando Cortés, [ca. 1943] (Box 20, Folder 251-73)
  - (124) The Rise of Fernando Cortés, 1943-45 (Box 21, Folder 274-80)
    See also: Oversize, Box 35, folder 437
  - (130) Memorial and Proposals of Señor Don José Martín, [ca. 1945] (Box 21, Folder 281)
  - (131) "Three Studies on the Same Subject", 1945-46 (Box 21, Folder 282-92)
  - (135) Nueva Bibliografía del Siglo XVI, Suplemento to a las Bibliografías de Don Joaquín García Icazbalceta, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 293)
  - (135) Nueva Bibliografía del Siglo XVI, Suplemento to a las Bibliografías de Don Joaquín García Icazbalceta, 1932, 1934 (Box 22, Folder 294-300)
    See also: Oversize, Box 35, folder 438
  - (136) "The Last Will of Pedro de Alvarado", 1946 (Box 22, Folder 301)
  - (137) [Review] Hernan Cortes, 1946-47 (Box 22, Folder 302)
  - (138) "Saints' Names in California", 1947 (Box 22, Folder 303)
  - (141) "Peter Martyr and his Works", [ca. 1947] (Box 23, Folder 304-05)
  - (142) "Descent on California", [ca. 1947] (Box 23, Folder 306)
  - (145) "Francisco López de Gómara", 1948 (Box 23, Folder 307-09)
  - (148) "Marco Polo's Narrative becomes Propaganda", 1947, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 310-18)
    See also: Oversize, Box 35, folder 439
  - (149-151) "Albert Little Bancroft", 1950 (Box 23, Folder 319-31)
  - (157) Memoirs of Edward Bosqui, [ca. 1952] (Box 24, Folder 332)
  - (166) "Henri Ternaux", [ca. 1955] (Box 24, Folder 333)
    See also: Oversize, Box 35, folder 440
  - (167) Peter Pond, 1955 (Box 24, Folder 334-37)
- Research Files, 1912-62; Series III; 6; (11 boxes)
  Series III, Research Files, is housed in Boxes 25-33. The material is arranged alphabetically by titles Wagner supplied or subject titles. Where possible, the material has been arranged in the same manner as Series II. Miscellaneous papers are housed at the end of the series.
  - American Book Clubs, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 338)
  - Bancroft Library: notes, 1915, 1939 (Box 25, Folder 339-40)
  - British Economic Tracts Bibliography
    - Page format, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 341-48)
    - Page format, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 349-59)
    - Card format, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 360)
    - Card format, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 361)
    - Card format, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 362)
    - Card format, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 363)
  - Background notes on economic history (Box 30.1, Folder 363.1-12)
    - and economists